JOHN HEBRON

Abbeville, LA (Remote) | johnhebron@gmail.com

Engineer with over 5 years experience in decomposing Rails monoliths and building microservices and APIs. I thrive at researching, communicating, and documenting and am a huge proponent of culture and DEI.

I'm looking for somewhere that I can be a culture "add" not just a culture "fit".

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

BIGCOMMERCE, Austin, TX

Feb 2013 - Dec 2022

Software Engineer II, Billing Platform Team

(2020-2022)

- Led a team of 3 engineers through planning and execution of multiple new features to allow "private labeling" for resellers and enabled numerous +\$1M partnerships
- Helped design and implement a new, rescoped v2 API, transitioning from REST to RPC, allowing the company to resell services with any frontend
- Acted as Product Owner and worked cross-departmentally to ensure project success
- Built dashboards to identify attacks and implemented middleware to stop or throttle tens of thousands of requests per minute at peak
- Served as On Call, Deploy Manager, and Production Support on rotation and developed internal, customer-friendly docs which reduced our weekly contacts by well over half
- Stepped up to own, document, fix, and grow the abandoned Partner APIs after a shift in company vision and priority made them a focus for company performance and success in 2021
- Worked heavily with product provisioning, which involves over 4 core systems and numerous secondary systems and libraries, spanning Ruby, PHP, Scala, and NodeJS services

Software Engineer I, Billing Platform Team

(2018-2020)

- Setup and configured infrastructure for new services, including containerization, configuration of MySQL, Redis/Resque, RabbitMQ/Protorabbit, CircleCI, and deployment to GCS, AWS, and Heroku
- Updated core legacy domains to extract billing logic and introduce new flexibility which empowered the pricing decisions that ultimately grew the company through IPO
- Served as On Call, Deploy Manager, and Production Support on rotation
- Participated in, and often led, all SCRUM ceremonies for a team of ~15 and was a top contributor to the internal knowledge base

Technical Support Manager

(2015-2018)

- Led a team of 15-20 front-line technical support agents and a team of 5 technical support leads
- Built a PHP service to aggregate and present agent performance metrics, causing an immediate and sustained jump in CSAT

Technical Outsource Trainer

(2014-2015)

Technical Support: Phone/Chat/Email & Escalations

(2013-2014)

RELEVANT SKILLS AND TECHNOLOGIES

Languages: Ruby, PHP, Javascript, exposure to Scala **Frameworks:** Ruby on Rails, Sinatra, Laravel, NodeJS

Tools & Services: Docker, MySQL/PostgreSQL, Redis/Resque, RabbitMQ/Protorabbit,

Travis/CircleCI, GCS/AWS/Heroku, SOAP/REST, gRPC/Protobuf

Concepts: Decomposing Rails monoliths, microservices, testing, CI/CD, upgrading Rails,

building APIs, billing and provisioning concepts, technical documentation

CULTURAL CONTRIBUTIONS AND VOLUNTEERING AT WORK

- Served as a mentor/speaker during multiple events with the amazing women from <u>TechWomen</u> and the Anne Richard's School
- Passionate about growing teams that communicate well both internally and externally
- Founded and led <u>BigCommerce's BProud LGBTQ+ ERG</u> for 3+ years, mentored two following ERGs
- Secured funding and participation for 2 years of the local LGBTQIA+ Hackouts
- Collected and donated enough toys for over 3,000 children over 6 years for Partnerships for Children
- Sponsored and participated in the annual fundraiser for the Texas Humane Heroes for 5 years
- Have led or participated in almost every cultural activity within BigCommerce for the past 10 years (seriously)

EDUCATION

Louisiana State University

Baton Rouge, LA

May 2012

Bachelor of Interdisciplinary Studies: Concentrations in English, Theatre, Sociology, and Film and Media Arts